Finding Aid for the Phyllis Diller papers, 1934-2011 LSC.1893
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Sheet Music, 1934-Circa 1980
  - "The Beautiful Phyllis Diller Show" TV series., October 1968
    - Sheet Music, November 10, 1968 (Box 45, Folder 11)
      Sheet music for Season One, Episode Nine. Songs including "Carrie Nation Rag" and "Carrie Button." (7 out of 11, see Box 46, Folders 3-6)
    - Sheet Music, September 15, 1968 (Box 46, Folder 1)
      Sheet music for Season One, Episode One. Songs including "James Knox Polka," "Back to Bach," "Sing Sing Sing," and ""Chicken Playoff"." (4 of 5)
    - Sheet Music, September 15, 1968 (Box 46, Folder 2)
      Sheet music for Season One, Episode One. Songs including "James Knox Polka." (5 of 5)
    - Sheet Music, November 10, 1968 (Box 46, Folder 3)
      Sheet music for Season One, Episode Nine. Songs including "Carrie Nation Rag." (8 of 11)
    - Sheet Music, November 10, 1968 (Box 46, Folder 4)
      Sheet music for Season One, Episode Nine. Songs including "Learn to Fly." (9 of 11)
    - Sheet Music, November 10, 1968 (Box 46, Folder 5)
      Sheet music for Season One, Episode Nine. Songs including "Dirty Movies" and "If I Had a Hammer." (10 of 11)
    - Sheet Music, November 10, 1968 (Box 46, Folder 6)
      Sheet music for Season One, Episode Nine. Songs including "If I Had a Hammer." (11 of 11)
    - Sheet Music, November 17, 1968 (Box 46, Folder 7)
      Sheet music for Season One, Episode Ten. Songs including "Singin' in the Rain." (5 of 10)
    - Sheet Music, November 17, 1968 (Box 46, Folder 8)
      Sheet music for Season One, Episode Ten. Songs including "Finian's Medley." (6 of 10)
    - Sheet Music, November 17, 1968 (Box 46, Folder 9)
      Sheet music for Season One, Episode Ten. Songs including "Finian's Medley." (7 of 10)
    - Sheet Music, November 17, 1968 (Box 46, Folder 10)
      Sheet music for Season One, Episode Ten. Songs including "Gee Mr. Webster." (8 of 10)
    - Sheet Music, November 17, 1968 (Box 46, Folder 11)
      Sheet music for Season One, Episode Ten. Songs including "Communication Gap." (9 of 10, see Box 47, Folder 1)
    - Sheet Music, November 17, 1968 (Box 47, Folder 1)
      Sheet music for Season One, Episode Ten. Songs including "Communication Gap." (10 of 10)
    - Sheet Music, September 22, 1968 (Box 47, Folder 2)
      Sheet music for Season One, Episode Two. Songs including "Look of Love." (1 of 2).
    - Sheet Music, October 6, 1968 (Box 47, Folder 3)
      Sheet music for Season One, Episode Four. Songs including "We Jog." (5 of 10)
    - Sheet Music, October 6, 1968 (Box 47, Folder 4)
      Sheet music for Season One, Episode Four. Songs including: "We Jog." (6 of 10)
    - Sheet Music, October 6, 1968 (Box 47, Folder 5)
      Sheet music for Season One, Episode Four. Songs including "Susan B. Anthony" and "The Men in My Little Girl's Life." (7 of 10)
    - Sheet Music, October 6, 1968 (Box 47, Folder 6)
      Sheet music for Season One, Episode Four. Songs including "The Men in My Little Girl's Life." (8 of 10)
    - Sheet Music, October 6, 1968 (Box 47, Folder 7)
      Sheet music for Season One, Episode Four. Songs including "Nobody Wants to Pet." (9 of 10)
    - Sheet Music, October 6, 1968 (Box 47, Folder 8)
      Sheet music for Season One, Episode Four. Songs including "Nobody Wants to Pet." (10 if 10)
    - Sheet Music, October 20, 1968 (Box 47, Folder 9)
      Sheet music for Season One, Episode Six. Songs including "The Man I Love." (7 of 8)
    - Sheet Music, October 20, 1968 (Box 47, Folder 10)
      Sheet music for Season One, Episode Six. Songs including "Gardner." (8 of 8)
    - Sheet Music, November 3, 1968 (Box 47, Folder 11)
      Sheet music for Season One, Episode Eight. Songs including "I Lost My Kidney in Sidney" and "Pooh Pooh P.T. Barnum." (10 of 11)
    - Sheet Music, November 3, 1968 (Box 47, Folder 12)
      Sheet music for Season One, Episode Eight. Songs including "Pooh Pooh P.T. Barnum" and "Honey." (11 of 11)
    - Sheet Music, September 29, 1968 (Box 48, Folder 2)
      Sheet music for Season One, Episode Three. Songs including "Everyday Housewife". (9 of 9)
  - Unlabeled Sheet Music, Undated
    Unlabeled sheet music from various periods in Diller's career. Series contains a small amount of handwritten sheet music presumably written for Diller's live performances and television appearances (contained in folders 1-4), and a substantial amount of pre-published sheet music from various periods. Notable songs include "Phyllis' Theme" by Ed Robards; "Firestone Theme Song/Theme Song--Phyllis Diller"; "Spinning Song" by F. Mendelssohn; "The Ghoul-Friend" by Murray Grand and June Carroll; and "Phyllis Fugue," written by Diller in 1937. Pre-published sheet music mostly consists of standards from the American songbook (i.e. "Happiness Is A Thing Called Joe" by E.Y. Harburg and Harold Arlen and "These Foolish Things Remind Me of You" by Holt Marvlel, Jack Strachey, and Harry Link), popular American songs (i.e. "New York, New York" by Kander and Ebb; "The Sound of Silence" by Paul Simon and Art Garfunkel), opera music (i.e. Puccini's "La Boheme"), and classical music.
    - Sheet Music, Undated (Box 31, Folder 7)
      Unlabelled sheet music that appears to have been composed specifically for Diller's performances.
    - Sheet Music, Undated (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - Sheet Music, Undated (Box 32, Folder 2)
    - Sheet Music, Undated (Box 32, Folder 3)
    - Sheet Music, Undated (Box 32, Folder 4)
      Published sheet music
    - Sheet Music, Undated (Box 32, Folder 5)
      Published sheet music.
    - Sheet Music, Undated (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Sheet Music, Undated (Box 33, Folder 2)
    - Sheet Music, Undated (Box 33, Folder 3)
    - Sheet Music, Undated (Box 33, Folder 4)
    - Sheet Music, Undated (Box 33, Folder 5)
    - Sheet Music, Undated (Box 34, Folder 1)
    - Sheet Music, Undated (Box 34, Folder 2)
    - Sheet Music, Undated (Box 34, Folder 3)
    - Sheet Music, Undated. (Box 34, Folder 4)
- Clippings, 1957-2011
  Includes clippings from newspapers, magazines, etc. Clippings occasionally include notes or comments written on the articles by Diller. Several years are arranged out of chronological order, maintaining Diller's original organization.
  - Clippings, 1957-1965 (Box 48, Folder 6)
  - Clippings, 1966-1969 (Box 48, Folder 7)
  - Clippings, 1970-1973 (Box 48, Folder 8)
  - Clippings, 1974-1982 (Box 49, Folder 1)
  - Clippings, 1983-1986 (Box 49, Folder 2)
    1 of 2, see 57.4
  - Clippings, 1989 (Box 49, Folder 3)
    1 of 2
  - Clippings, 1989 (Box 49, Folder 4)
    2 of 2
  - Clippings, 1987 (Box 49, Folder 5)
  - Clippings, 1988 (Box 49, Folder 6)
  - Clippings, 1990 (Box 50, Folder 1)
  - Clippings, 1991 (Box 50, Folder 2)
  - Clippings, 1991 (Box 50, Folder 3)
  - Clippings, 1992 (Box 50, Folder 4)
    1 of 3
  - Clippings, 1992 (Box 50, Folder 5)
    2 of 3
  - Clippings, 1992 (Box 50, Folder 6)
    3 of 3
  - Clippings, 1993 (Box 50, Folder 7)
    1 of 9
  - Clippings, 1993 (Box 50, Folder 8)
    2 of 9
  - Clippings, 1993 (Box 51, Folder 1)
    3 of 9
  - Clippings, 1993 (Box 51, Folder 2)
    4 of 9
  - Clippings, 1993 (Box 51, Folder 3)
    5 of 9
  - Clippings, 1993 (Box 51, Folder 4)
    6 of 9
  - Clippings, 1993 (Box 51, Folder 5)
    7 of 9
  - Clippings, 1993 (Box 51, Folder 6)
    8 of 9
  - Clippings, 1993 (Box 52, Folder 1)
    9 of 9
  - Clippings, 1994 (Box 52, Folder 2)
    1 of 11
  - Clippings, 1994 (Box 52, Folder 3)
    2 of 11
  - Clippings, 1994 (Box 52, Folder 4)
    3 of 11
  - Clippings, 1994 (Box 52, Folder 5)
    4 of 11
  - Clippings, 1994 (Box 52, Folder 6)
    5 of 11
  - Clippings, 1994 (Box 52, Folder 7)
    6 of 11
  - Clippings, 1994 (Box 53, Folder 1)
    7 of 11
  - Clippings, 1994 (Box 53, Folder 2)
    8 of 11
  - Clippings, 1994 (Box 53, Folder 3)
    9 of 11
  - Clippings, 1994 (Box 53, Folder 4)
    10 of 11
  - Clippings, 1994 (Box 53, Folder 5)
    11 of 11
  - Clippings, 1995 (Box 53, Folder 6)
  - Clippings, 1995 (Box 53, Folder 7)
  - Clippings, 1995 (Box 54, Folder 1)
  - Clippings, 1995 (Box 54, Folder 2)
  - Clippings, 1995 (Box 54, Folder 3)
  - Clippings, 1995 (Box 54, Folder 4)
  - Clippings, 1995 (Box 54, Folder 5)
  - Clippings, 1995 (Box 54, Folder 6)
    8 of 11, see Box 57, Folders 1-3
  - Clippings, 1998 (Box 55, Folder 1)
    1 of 4
  - Clippings, 1998 (Box 55, Folder 2)
    2 of 4
  - Clippings, 1998 (Box 55, Folder 3)
    3 of 4, see Box 58, Folder 3
  - Clippings, 1997 (Box 55, Folder 4)
    1 of 7
  - Clippings, 1997 (Box 55, Folder 5)
    2 of 7
  - Clippings, 1997 (Box 55, Folder 6)
    3 of 7
  - Clippings, 1997 (Box 55, Folder 7)
    4 of 7
  - Clippings, 1997 (Box 56, Folder 1)
    5 of 7
  - Clippings, 1997 (Box 56, Folder 2)
    6 of 8, see Box 58, Folders 1 and 2
  - Clippings, 1996 (Box 56, Folder 3)
  - Clippings, 1996 (Box 56, Folder 4)
  - Clippings, 1996 (Box 56, Folder 5)
  - Clippings, 1996 (Box 56, Folder 6)
  - Clippings, 1996 (Box 56, Folder 7)
    5 of 7, see Box 57, Folders 5 and 6
  - Clippings, 1995 (Box 57, Folder 1)
  - Clippings, 1995 (Box 57, Folder 2)
  - Clippings, 1995 (Box 57, Folder 3)
  - Clippings, 1984 (Box 57, Folder 4)
  - Clippings, 1996 (Box 57, Folder 5)
    6 of 7
  - Clippings, 1996 (Box 57, Folder 6)
    7 of 7
  - Clippings, 1997 (Box 58, Folder 1)
    7 of 8
  - Clippings, 1997 (Box 58, Folder 2)
    8 of 8
  - Clippings, 1998 (Box 58, Folder 3)
    4 of 4
  - Clippings, 1999 (Box 58, Folder 4)
  - Clippings, 2000 (Box 58, Folder 5)
  - Clippings, 2001 (Box 58, Folder 6)
  - Clippings, 2001 (Box 58, Folder 7)
  - Clippings, 2001 (Box 59, Folder 1)
    3 of 4
  - Clippings, 2001 (Box 59, Folder 2)
  - Clippings, 2002 (Box 59, Folder 3)
  - Clippings, 2002 (Box 59, Folder 4)
  - Clippings, 2002 (Box 59, Folder 5)
  - Clippings, 2002 (Box 59, Folder 6)
  - Clippings, 2003 (Box 60, Folder 1)
  - Clippings, 2003 (Box 60, Folder 2)
  - Clippings, 2003 (Box 60, Folder 3)
  - Clippings, 2003 (Box 60, Folder 4)
  - Clippings, 2004 (Box 60, Folder 5)
  - Clippings, 2004 (Box 60, Folder 6)
  - Clippings, 2004 (Box 61, Folder 1)
  - Clippings, 2005 (Box 61, Folder 2)
  - Clippings, 2005 (Box 61, Folder 3)
  - Clippings, 2005 (Box 61, Folder 4)
  - Clippings, 2005 (Box 61, Folder 5)
  - Clippings, 2006 (Box 62, Folder 1)
  - Clippings, 2007 (Box 62, Folder 2)
  - Clippings, 2007 (Box 62, Folder 3)
  - Clippings, 2007 (Box 62, Folder 4)
  - Clippings, 2007 (Box 62, Folder 5)
  - Clippings, 2008-09 (Box 63, Folder 1)
  - Clippings, 2010 (Box 63, Folder 2)
  - Clippings, 2011 (Box 63, Folder 3)
    This folder also includes a small number of undated articles from a box labeled "2010-11."
  - Clippings, Undated (Box 63, Folder 4)
    Undated clippings labeled "miscellaneous." Includes clips from circa 1960 through the 1990s and 2000s (most clippings appear to be from the latter decades).
- Publications, 1951-2009
  Includes books and articles written by Diller and books featuring Diller.
  - "A Letter to Dad" by Diller, May 1951 (Box 64, Folder 1)
    Magazine: "Your Life," Vol. 28, No. 5 (May 1951). Includes an article titled "A Letter to Dad" by Diller.
  - "Phyllis Diller's Housekeeping Hints", 1966 (Box 64, Folder 2)
    Book: "Phyllis Diller's Housekeeping Hints." New York: Doubleday and Company, Inc., 1966.
  - "Phyllis Diller's Marriage Manual", 1967 (Box 64, Folder 3)
    Book: "Phyllis Diller's Marriage Manual." New York: Doubleday and Company, Inc., 1966.
  - "The Complete Mother", 1969 (Box 64, Folder 4)
    Book: Diller, Phyllis. "The Complete Mother." New York: Doubleday and Company, Inc., 1969.
  - "Like a Lampshade in a Whorehouse: My Life in Comedy", 2005 (Box 64, Folder 5)
    Book: Diller, Phyllis. "Like a Lampshade in a Whorehouse: My Life in Comedy." New York: Penguin Group (USA), Inc., 2005.
  - "Celebrity Stew", 2003 (Box 64, Folder 6)
    Book: Pearlstein, Leo. "Celebrity Stew." Steve Allen, foreword. Hollywood Circle Press, 2003. Pre-publication draft.
  - "Pat Rocco DARED!", 2009 (Box 64, Folder 7)
    Book: Rocco, Pat. "Pat Rocco DARED!" P.R. Productions, 2009.
- Playbills and programs, 1971-2006
  Includes playbills, programs, and pamphlets for Diller's various performances and appearances.
  - Playbills and programs, Circa 1960-1991 (Box 65, Folder 1)
    Includes press kit for "The Best of Broadway Presents: The Phyllis Diller Show" (Diller's first television special, different from her sitcom of the same name). See also: Boxes 29, 30, and 48 in the "Sheet Music" series (which contain sheet music that was likely from this special).
  - Playbills and programs, 1995 (Box 65, Folder 2)
  - Playbills and programs, 1996 (Box 65, Folder 3)
  - Playbills and programs, 1996-97 (Box 65, Folder 4)
  - Playbills and programs, 1996-1997 (Box 65, Folder 5)
  - Playbills and programs, 1998-1999 (Box 65, Folder 6)
  - Playbills and programs, 2000 (Box 66, Folder 1)
  - Playbills and programs, 2000 (Box 66, Folder 2)
  - Playbills and programs, 2000-06 (Box 66, Folder 3)
  - Playbills and programs, Undated (Box 66, Folder 4)
- Ephemera and souvenirs, Circa 1935 to 2011
  Includes Mayor Lewis Brown, Jr.'s proclamation of "Phyllis Diller Day" in San Francisco, CA; press materials from early stage and television performances in the 1950s; a signed check by George Gershwin; "Family Guy" trading card; press material for Phyllis Diller's Original Recipe Chili.
  - Birthday celebration poster, July 16, 1998 (Box 63, Folder 5)
    Poster for Phyllis Diller's 81st birthday celebration and screening of the film "The Private Navy of Sergeant O'Farrell," co-starring Bob Hope. The event took place at Akebono Theatre.
  - Ephemera and souvenirs, Circa 1950-2011 (Box 67, Folder 1)
    Includes Mayor Lewis Brown, Jr.'s proclamation of "Phyllis Diller Day" in San Francisco, CA; press materials from early stage and television performances in the 1950s; "Family Guy" trading card; press material for Phyllis Diller's Original Recipe Chili.
  - Check from George Gershwin, 1935 (Box 67, Folder 2)
    A framed signed check by George Gershwin.
  - Diller Gin game, Undated (Box 70, Folder 1)
    Diller Gin, a game described as "A new card game created by Phyllis Diller- America's funny lady."
- Media, 1959-2000
  Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
  Includes vinyl LPs, film, audio cassette tapes, compact discs, and VHS tapes.
  - Bob Costas Anecdote for Phyllis Diller, August, 22, 1995 (Box 68, Folder 1)
    Labeled: Bob Costas Anecdote for Phyllis Diller, Production Consultants, St. Louis 4:366; Dolby B. 8/22/95. Includes a letter from Kay Reller. Format: Audio cassette.
  - "Only in Hollywood" TV special, November 5, 1997 (Box 68, Folder 2)
    "Only in Hollywood" TV special, which aired on E! Entertainment Television. Labeled: Dub: 11/5/97, Total running time: 60:00. The program was sent to Diller by Jonah Borris at E! Entertainment Television, and includes a note from him. Format: VHS cassette.
  - "Diller" by Aileen E. Smith, 2000 (Box 68, Folder 3)
    A recording of Aileen E. Smith's song "Diller," a song about Diller set to the tune of Michael Jackson's "Thriller." The package contains a letter from Smith and lyrics to the song.
    1 CD.
    Special equipment or further processing may be required for viewing. To access digital materials you must notify the reference desk in advance of your visit.
  - "Phyllis Diller Laughs" record, 1961 (Box 69, Folder 1)
    "Phyllis Diller Laughs." Format: LP record.
  - "Are You Ready For Phyllis Diller?" record, 1962 (Box 69, Folder 2)
    "Are You Ready For Phyllis Diller?." Format: LP record.
  - "The Best of Phyllis Diller" record, 1965 (Box 69, Folder 3)
    "The Best of Phyllis Diller." Format: LP record.
  - "'On the Lam': Original Motion Picture Soundtrack" record, 1967 (Box 69, Folder 4)
    "'On the Lam': Original Motion Picture Soundtrack." Format: LP record.
  - "What's Left of Phyllis Diller" record, 1967 (Box 69, Folder 5)
    "What's Left of Phyllis Diller." Format: LP record.
  - "Born to Sing" record, 1970 (Box 69, Folder 6)
    Diller, Phyllis. "Born to Sing." Format: LP record.
- Costumes, Circa 1975 and undated
  Costume pieces worn by Diller in various performances.
  - Sequin dress, Circa 1975 (Box 76)
    Diller's dress in blue, red, green and gold sequins having an over blousing with open oval sections, removable center panel with leaf shape detailing, by Australian studio designer for Australian tour.
  - Feathered boa, Undated (Box 72)
    Diller's red and blue feathered boa, used on various tours.
  - Wig, Undated (Box 73)
    Diller's gray fright wig, used on various tours.
  - Straw hat, Undated (Box 74)
    Diller's yellow straw hat with attached matching flowers and leaves, used on various tours. Housed in a clear hatbox. Hatboxes were specially ordered by Diller's daughter and assistant, Stephanie Waldron, so that Diller could display hats easily.
  - Silver Shoes and "With Love Phyllis Diller" pocket knife, Undated (Box 75)
    Diller's silver shoes, used in various performances.